Danyang Chen

My Site: stevechanvii.me | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/danyang-chen-19a753169/

Career Objective

A med-level software developer with 1.5 years of experience. With the focus of frontend development, fast learning, critical thinking and effective communication in teamwork are well- developed. To become a full-stack developer/ network security specialist will be my long-term goal.

Technical Skills

- Strong scripting and coding skills, e.g. JavaScript (ES6), React, React Native, Gatsby.js, Material
 UI, P5.js, HTML/CSS, SCSS, JSS, GraphQL, RESTful APIs, Git and more;
- Proficient with MongoDB, Firebase, MySQL, SQL Server and Oracle SQL;
- Familiar with deploying and hosting on clouds AWS, Azure and Heroku;
- Advanced Photoshop skills in designing good-looking icons and images;
- Strong communication skills and multilingual skills, e.g. English, Mandarin and Cantonese.

Certifications

- AWS Certified Developer Associate
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals
- NAATI Certified Interpreter (Mandarin and English)
- Getty Images Certified Photographer and Contributor

Work Experience

OSCER TRADING PTY LTD

Melbourne, Australia

Frontend developer

July 2021 – Present

Developed <u>oscer.ai</u>, an AI-based medical training single page application, with content management, payment and permission-based access control.

- Analysing product requirements and business logic, designing system architecture, and completing
 the project development in React framewok, ensure the product runing consistently across
 different platforms, browsers and devices;
- Managing a frontend and backend devops pipeline with manual and automated components, creating high-level algorithms for transactional APIs and scripting to perform complex data manipulation;
- Testing the project by Cypress framework, ensure the product is running correctly before delivery, performing cost benefit analyses by AB testing, and assist the user growth team to analyse user needs by Google Analytics, Facebook Pixel and Mixpanel.

A: Sydney, NSW 2134 | M: 0413081106 | E: chendanyangvii@gmail.com

FGT ENTERPRISES PTY LTD

Melbourne, Australia

Frontend developer

July 2020 - July 2021

Developed the company's website (<u>FIT</u> and <u>UCAT</u>) to achieve reusable mobile responsive, response speed, SEO and content management.

- Using Gatsby.js to independently design and develop the responsive company website (FIT and UCAT), using Buttercms to achieve content management and separate the front and back ends to improve the response speed;
- Applied SEO, using SEO standards, Google Analytics and Google Search Console to significantly improve web traffic achieved about 30% active user growth in most two recent months;
- Developed and deployed the website using React & Redux, Gatsby framework;

Codejoy Melbourne, Australia

Frontend developer

Feb 2020 – May 2020

- Working at a startup which just finished product design and research, but was short of developers;
- Developed an alpha **Android App** based on **Kotlin**. Developed pose estimation games by **JavaScript**;
- Being a small Agile team which needs to handle urgent and unplanned tasks in a limited time;

Projects

- SteveChanVII.me (Demo | GitHub)
 - My portfolio developed by React and Gatsby framework, and deployed in AWS;
 - Use GraphQL to lazy loading images for faster response;
 - Responsive design by SCSS framework with beautiful animation.
- Poke Allergist (<u>Google Play</u> | <u>GitHub</u>)
 - Android and iOS Apps for people who suffer from allergy and intolerance.
 - Led a successful agile team to complete a cross-platform application by React Native;
 - Integrating Google Machine Learning for text recognition and allergies detection;
- Developer Portfolio (Demo | GitHub)
 - A social network for developers using MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js);
 - **Redux** is used for state management, and JSON Web Token (**JWT**) for user authentication;
 - O Deployed in Heroku.

Education

Monash University

Melbourne, VIC

Master of Information Technology

Graduated Oct 2019

- Award Information Technology International Merit Scholarship
- Winner of Post Graduate Industry Experience 2019.

Reference

References available upon request